Never forget why you are the church.
Some good stuff.
If you were to turn your Bibles to Romans chapter 8, sometimes
it's okay to have an extended worship session.
Amen?
And so when God's working, you just let them continue to work.
But Romans chapter 8, thank you, worship team, for leading us.
Thank you for being flexible like that.
Thank you for audio visual.
I know those moments are not always the easiest,
but thank you for keeping up with us.
And man, God is just good, is he not?
It's so good.
So this morning, I had every intention.
of finishing chapter 8 in Romans.
And you know how intentions are.
You know what I'm saying?
They're pretty cool for a moment, but we will not be finishing chapter 8.
We're gonna do this in two parts going through these
verses to conclude this great chapter.
But before we get there, in Romans chapter 8, have
you ever had someone try to sell you something?
Oh, I just hit a nerve there.
Yeah?
Back in the day, you know, I was doing some research on sales, tactics,
and salesmanship and all things, and I have no lot of tail.
When I went to college, you might be thinking, hey, you know, what seminary did you go to?
What Bible college did you go to?
I went to the great religious school
of Middle Tennessee State University.
Amen?
And went into the very spiritual concrete
program, but my focus was production, sales, and service.
I wanted to sell stuff.
And that's what I wanted to do.
That's what I was going to be good at.
my dad has always done for as long as I can remember.
And so, but I was looking at, why,
what I just said, hit a nerve.
And I don't know if you remember, maybe you don't.
Maybe you're either too young or maybe you remember like it was yesterday.
Does anyone remember door-to- door vacuum salesman's?
Was that a big thing back in the day?
It evidently was?
Because there's a lot of research I can do about it.
A salesman would come to your house and attempt to get
you to buy a brand new state of the art vacuum.
Anyone ever had that happen?
Has anyone ever had someone come up to their doorstep and say, I want to sell you a vacuum?
Okay, all right.
Now, if you fast forward to 2025, it's pest control.
You know what I'm saying?
Like, man, you can't get rid of those guys.
But what would be the process of this vacuum presentation?
Well, he would get the vacuum out and show how high powered it was.
I mean, there's, like, actual logistics here early on
in the 1920s to the 1960s, maybe
back in the day when they were coming to your house.
There was a dirt on the floor technique.
So what they would do is they would take a big old clump of
dirt, they'd throw it on the floor, and you'd be like, what are you doing?
And then they clean it up with that vacuum, right?
It'd be a dramatic display of how good that product was.
Moving along in the 70s and 80s, the salesman began to up the pressure.
It was a common tactic to find hidden dust and mites in
the carpet that their superior vacuum would have no problem, cleaning up.
As a matter of fact, I remember anyone ever know, anyone
ever heard of Rainsoft, the water company that comes into your house?
So we bought our house in 2019.
Uh, we were just about to have, uh, either
we were just about to have, or we already had, well, it wouldn't have been,
don't even know what's going on.
I think River was in the tummy in 2019, 2020.
What is River's birthday?
anyway, we'll talk about that later.
I promise you, I love my child.
But anyway, February 19, 2020.
I got it, okay?
So, yeah, she was in the belly at this time, and so we're sitting there,
and this dude says, Hey, listen, if you come and let me do this presentation, I'll give
you a $50 Home Depot gift card.
I'm thinking, man, I got a new house, probably got to fix some things up, don't know how, but
I can go buy stuff to do it, you know?
And so $50, by the way.
That's a sham, you know what I'm saying?
Where you gonna buy a couple, you know, light bulbs.
But either way, he came in, man, and he put that water
thing, and he said, hey, do you drink out of tat water?
I said, no, we don't really drink out of tap water.
We have a refrigerator that has, you know, a thing.
He said, okay, well, just let's get your water out, and I'm gonna show you how nasty it is.
man, I'm telling you what, it was the nastiest stuff.
He put whatever stuff he went in, and it's like, are we actually
bathing and washing our dishes and doing brushing our teeth with this water?
And I'm scared of death.
Then he said, you know, you don't want your little girl to be hindered by this?
And I was like, No, you sure right.
I do not.
I mean, I was scared to death.
Then he hits me with that price.
And he's like, It's only this much for, you know, the rest of
your life, you know what I'm saying?
But, man, it was so high pressured.
It was all this, it was that, and man, it was fear that, but here's the thing.
I started asking questions.
See, what a salesman does not want.
Are questions.
Every spell is going to tell you, they love answering questions, but in
reality, they would much rather show you the product,
ring up your credit card, or ring you up for a new
one, and ask questions later.
Why?
Because questions lead to exposure.
Amen?
Well, what about the warranty?
What about the interest rate?
Will it work for this or just that?
Well, what about the reviews or can you give me maybe some some
more information about this or that, whatever it is?
The best products, answer all the questions through its excellent function.
That's why that salesman would bring the vacuum
in, throw the stuff out, and clean it up because they wanted you
to know, there's your answer to the questions.
Doesn't really matter.
They want you to think it's so good.
Doesn't matter the cost, doesn't matter the payments, doesn't
matter anything, just ring me up.
Well, here's the thing.
You might be thinking, what does this have to do with
Romans chapter 8?
And that would be a good question, but here's here's what I want you to understand.
Paul here is not selling a product.
There are no products sold in the Bible.
There are going to be preachers that try to preach in such a way that it's
almost as if they're giving a selling seminar for the truth in God's word.
I don't have to sell you this.
It's good enough.
If you just read it, you'll want to receive it.
So he's not selling a product.
He is presenting a purpose plan
and promise of God.
And he does so by asking the questions
himself that touch our deepest need.
He doesn't want any confusion on what God offers
us through Jesus Christ.
So this morning, we're going to go over these questions and answers
and see if we are persuaded of God's love and promise.
If you're in your Bible, we're going to be in Romans chapter 8,
verse 31, we're going to read all the way through 39.
If you're there, say read.
What shall we then say to these things?
If God be for us, who can be against us?
He that spared not his own son, but delivered him up for
us all, how shall he not with him also freely give us all things?
Who shall lay anything to the charge of God's elect?
It is God that justifieth.
Who is he that condemneth?
It is Christ that died, yea, rather, that is risen
again who is even at the right hand of God, who also maketh
intercession for us.
Who shall separate us from the love of Christ.
Shall tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness,
or peril, or sword, as it is written, for
thy sake, we are killed all the day long.
We are accounted as sheep for the slaughter.
Nay, in all these things, we are more than conquerors
through him that loved us.
Verse 38, I love it, for I am persuaded.
that neither death nor life, nor
angels, nor principalities, nor powers, nor things present, nor things
to come, nor height, nor death, nor any other creature, shall
be able to separate us from the love of God, which
is in Christ, Jesus, our Lord, somebody, say, amen in agreeance.
The title this morning is very simple.
are you persuaded.
Father, I thank you, Lord, for the church that we've already had.
And God, I thank you that the table is set for the hearts
that have been softened through the worship of Jesus.
And God, I pray that you give me power, clarity, and liberty to preach this message,
Lord, may I encourage God, whether it needs to be encouragement.
God.
May I uplift the people of God this morning, but also
challenge the people of God to trust you no matter what.
God, I pray for that one who might be here, God, who is
not saved, not born again, trying to live this life according
to their own merit, according to their own good deeds, God, I pray, they understand,
that is not the way.
The only way, the truth in life is Jesus himself,
so God, I pray they give their life over to you.
God, we thank you, God, I pray that we are not
just hearers, but doers, and those that have ears to hear, may they
hear, since Jesus' name pray.
And everybody said, amen.
Five questions that he answers for us.
He really, you know, questions and then answers.
But question one this morning is out of Romans 8, verse 31.
We kind of went over it last week.
We're going to go over again.
What shall we then say to these things?
If God before us, who can be against us?
Now, see, we ask this almost theoretically
in our time today.
I do believe that certain Christians have been
persecuted, even in America.
But I want you to know, by the way, there are
Christians that are persecuted everywhere else way more than we are here.
I forget exactly where it was, what country I'm thinking, maybe Nigeria.
There's been like 1000s upon 1000s upon, possibly
100,000 Christians killed in the last 20 years just for their faith.
Just for pronouncing and
declaring, Jesus is Lord of my life.
They've lost their life because of that proclamation.
But see, even in America, it may look different.
It may not look different, but there's persecution.
But the overwhelming majority of believers enjoy religious
freedoms unique compared to the rest of the world.
So when we say this, we say it, oh, well, if God be
for us, who can be against us, we kind of put that in terms of, I'm having a bad day.
So if God be for me, who can be against me?
Or, man, I'm low on gas and
I need to go find a gas station or man, I
got up this morning on the wrong side of bed.
If God can be for me, who can listen, that's all fine and God cares
about the little things, but the Romans that heard this,
it would be a lot more intense for them.
See, to the believer living in Rome, this question pierced right to the heart.
This was a practical question that applied directly
to their lives.
When Paul wrote this letter, a emperor was in
power named Nero.
Christianity was still quite new and it was not recognized
as a protected religious group yet.
Christianity at its foundation, denied the
excess and sensuality and immoral character of
all the other religions in the Roman culture.
It was truly a light in the darkness.
So, therefore, Christians were often persecuted and hated.
When Paul asked this seeming theoretical question,
it meant something to the believer in Rome.
They would hang on to this question with all they had.
They would realize that, hey, my life is threatened, but if God be
for me, who can be against me?
Man, my family is torn apart because we
had to scatter and leave and this and I was forced to flee,
but if God before me who can be against me.
See, this is a question they needed to
hear and trust the answer.
too.
But again, how do we apply this question today?
Church, I want you to know we need to enjoy the freedoms that we have today.
Because tomorrow it could be gone.
I'm not one of those preachers that want to preach all the time
that, hey, listen, you know, just get ready, get ready, get ready.
Don't live in fear of what is tomorrow?
That's not what I'm trying to say.
I'm trying to say, live for Jesus
today in the freedom you have.
Because it may become more difficult tomorrow.
I do believe that the silent majority are becoming more vocal about right values.
I will say that.
You're seeing a push for more right values.
Now, listen, those that are trying to push
the sinful and the world order and all
those things, they will always be louder.
That's how it's going to be.
But we're seeing a push for right values.
However, we don't just need right values.
Conservative laws are great and I support them, but that's
not going to stop what's coming.
To know the difference between right and wrong is important, but Jesus, hear me.
Jesus must be Lord.
Do not be fooled just because a politician, athlete, or celebrity
speaks out on behalf of common sense does not make them a believer.
You do realize that our culture goes through ebbs and flows.
Sometimes it's cool to be a Christian, sometimes it's not cool to be a Christian.
You can bet, you can go ahead and guarantee yourself, there are
those that they're gonna ride the wave, whatever it is.
Hey, I'll be a Christian if it gets me more followers than money.
And when it doesn't, hey, listen, what Christianity who?
By the way, listen, I think that our president has
done a great job.
I think, listen, if you think you could do the presidency better, then,
you know, so be it.
You wouldn't get voted in.
Amen?
So it doesn't really matter what you could do.
But either way, I think we should support our president.
We should support our Congress.
We don't necessarily tolerate the evil, but
we need to pray for them, support them in prayer, the Bible says.
But can I tell you something?
Somebody needs to tell our president that creating peace in the
world will not get him into heaven.
You hearing me?
Peace is great and good, and I like it.
I think that's a cool thing to go for, and we should pray for the
peace of Jerusalem, especially, but here's the thing.
We don't just need peace.
We need the prince of peace.
Somebody filled with a spirit in the White House needs to tell him exactly
what Peter told people of Israel in Acts 4.
It says right here, be it known unto you all, and to all the people
of Israel that by the name of Jesus, Christ
of Nazareth, whom you crucified, whom God raised
from the dead, even by him, does this man stand here before you whole?
This is the stone which was set at naught of you builders,
which has become the head of the corner, neither is there salvation
in any other.
For there is none other name under heaven given
among men whereby we must be saved.
You can't get saved any other way.
There is no entrance in heaven.
There's no there's no multiple doors.
Well, I gave you crane peace, and I gave this person peace,
and I did this good deed, and that's not how it works.
There's one way, one truth, one life, Jesus.
And he must be, Lord.
Y'all with me this morning.
Why do I say this?
Christianity cannot continue to be tolerated in our nation.
If you read, if you read, the Bible,
it's going to come a time when a toleration is going to end.
Our nation is too evil and wicked.
Therefore, at some point we will see a move back to persecution
of those who love Christ.
Think about it.
Why would they oppose us now anyway?
I mean, really.
The church has done everything but join the worldly ranks.
We must stand strong and courageous, even against the enemy.
Whether it happens today or years or even decades from now, we
can trust exactly what Paul said.
Romans 8, 31
again, what shall we then say to these things?
If God be for us, who can be against us?
Even if they oppose us.
And there will come a day when that opposition is far greater than it
is now, hear me, according to scripture, they will not be successful.
You cannot beat God.
Now, that's question one.
Question two, we're going to camp out a little bit longer on.
you're still with me and say, I'm here.
I'm glad.
Don't leave me now.
Romans 8.32.
It says this.
He that spared not his own son, but delivered him up for
us all, how shall he then, how
shall he not with him also freely give us all things?
When we hear this verse,
Our mind should find its way to Genesis 22.
Maybe you didn't know it was Genesis 22, but you should at least think about
a story in Genesis 22.
What does it mean that God did not spare his own son?
That word spare is the same term used in Genesis
22, verse 12, where it says this, and he said, lay
not thine hand upon the lad.
This is God speaking to Abraham.
Neither do thou anything unto him, for now I know that thou
fearest God, seeing thou hast not withheld
thy son, thine only son, for me.
Now let's just get here for a second.
Remember, Abraham, God gave him a covenant.
God made a promise with him.
that through your seed, I will make a great
nation and through that nation, and through your seed, every nation will be blessed.
Right?
I bless those who bless you, curse those who curse you.
It was a covenant between him and God.
Well, he kind of got out of pocket a little bit and he rushed God's plan.
And by the way, when you try to rush God, nothing good is going to ever happen.
So, you know, things happened, got complicated, but then Isaac came.
The covenant child.
And then God said, hey, I want you to go up and I want you to
offer Isaac unto me as a burn offering.
Now, why in the world would God require Isaac from Abraham?
Isaac was the promised child.
He was the covenant heir.
Also, God explicitly forbids human sacrifice in the law.
Leviticus 1821, and thou shalt not.
Let any of thy seed pass through the fire to Moloch,
neither shalt thou profane the name of thy God.
I am the Lord.
See, in the Old Testament times, the pagans
would have a god named Moloch or Moloch, whatever you want
to say, he's false, not real.
But either way, they would offer his children to him.
Leviticus 20, verse 2 and 5.
Again, he's staying this again.
Thou shalt say to the children of Israel, whosoever he be
of the children of Israel, or the strangers that so join in
Israel that giveth any of his seed unto Moloch, he shall
surely be put to death.
The people of the land shall stone him with stones.
And I will set my face against the man, and I
will cut him off from among his people, because he hath given of his seed,
and to mullet, to defile my sanctuary, and to profane my holy name.
And if the people of the land do anyways, hide their
eyes from the man, when he giveth of his seed unto Moloch,
and kill him not, then I will set my face against that
man against his family, and will cut him off, and all that go
a whooring after him, to commit whoredom with Moloch from among their people.
Listen, God didn't take this lightly.
God is the giver of life.
By the way, God takes life very seriously.
Deuteronomy 12, verse 30 and 31.
Take heed to thyself, that thou be not snared by following them.
After that they be destroyed from before thee, and that
thou inquire not after their God, saying, how do these nations
serve their gods?
Even so will I do likewise.
God's warning them.
Thou shalt not do so unto the Lord thy God, for every abomination
to the Lord, which ye hateth, have they done unto their
gods, for even their sons and their daughters.
They have burnt in the fire to their gods.
God hates human sacrifice.
But it was never about that for Abraham.
God was never going to let Isaac have one hair on his head be hurt.
But what this display of face showed was that Abraham did not
spare, that is, withhold.
Even Isaac from God.
What is the bigger picture that we see here in Romans 8?
It's Calvary.
The event in the land of Moriah would serve as a foretelling,
a foreshadowing of what would take place on Golgotha 2,000 years later.
When God did not withhold his only begotten son,
so that the world could be saved from their sins.
Now, I know what you're thinking, and if you're thinking this way, then I think
that you would look at the text correctly and see it in a
way that you should analytically.
Well, if God hates human sacrifice, why and how did he
sacrifice Jesus?
Wouldn't this be contrary to his expressed will?
Well, 1st off, there's 2 reasons why you're incorrect with thinking that way.
First off, Jesus wasn't just a man.
Jesus was truly man and truly God.
John 114 says, and the word was made flesh and dwelt
among us, and we beheld his glory, the glory as of the only begotten
of the Father, full of grace and truth.
If Jesus was only a man, then his sacrifice would
have been only temporary.
Not satisfactory to the holy and just standard of God.
Church, a man could never pay for the sins of the world because
of their own sins that they need paid for.
But Jesus was God in the flesh, therefore his
sacrifice was infinite and atoning for all who would receive.
But secondly, not only is Jesus just not an
ordinary man, he was fully man and fully God.
You say, explain that more.
I can't tell you, that's just who God is.
But secondly, God didn't sacrifice Jesus as
we see Abraham willing to sacrifice Isaac.
Let's go back to the book of John real quick.
John chapter one, verse one says this.
Now pay attention to the language here.
In the beginning was the word.
And the word was with God, and the word, was God.
Are y'all with me this morning?
Okay, in the beginning was the word, and the word was, with God,
and the word was God, and now let's look back at chapter one, verse 14.
It says, and the word was made flesh, and dwelt among us.
And we beheld his glory, the glory as of the only begotten of
the Father, full of grace and truth.
Hear me.
This is not an ordinary sacrifice that would
break the law of God because in sacrificing Jesus.
God did not withhold himself from us.
So if he did not withhold Jesus.
And by doing so to not withhold himself.
Now we get to the 2nd question.
In verse 32.
Everyone look at it.
He that spared not his own son.
But delivered him up for us all.
How shall he not with him?
Also freely give us all thanks.
If he did not spare his own son, will he also not freely give us all things?
Now, here's the thing.
What are all things?
I mean, that's an important question right there.
I mean, that's kind of a big deal.
Right?
It's one of those things, have you ever had someone say, hey, man, I got something that you can have.
I don't really need it anymore, but you need to take all of it.
You can't take a little bit of it.
You got to take all of it.
What do you usually do?
Well, I kinda know what's in there first.
Someone might just be trying to put all their trash on you, you know what I'm saying?
But this is not...
I mean, this is not what we're talking about.
We wanna know what God means by all.
It's very important.
See, some so-called preachers like to preach that this teaches God
will not withhold all of our earthly desires from us.
You want that car?
You want that house?
You want that raise?
You want that new whatever you want?
Well, you're in luck.
That's exactly what God wants for you.
So go and claim it.
The only.
The only issue with that.
Prosperity gospel is that it's not true.
Amen.
I mean, it's a pretty big issue, but that's the only issue is that it's false.
It's not real.
That's not the all that we're seeing here.
Listen, you may be in want on this earth, yet God still
gives us, you, all things freely.
How do we reconcile this?
The world puts all this all into what they have and
all the things that desire and want and go after.
But the person who's in want, who has nothing on this
world, still has all things freely given.
How do we restore and understand this?
Paul, or Peter, I believe, clears this up.
And 2nd Peter chapter one.
We're going to read the 1st 4 verses, it says that Simon and Peter, a
servant and an apostle of Jesus Christ, to them that have
obtained like precious faith with us to the righteousness of
God and our Savior, Jesus Christ.
Grace and peace be multiplied unto youth, and the knowledge of
God, and of Jesus our Lord.
According as his divine power, hath
given unto us all things.
Everyone say all.
All things that what?
pertain unto life and godliness.
Through the knowledge of him that hath called us to glory and
virtue, whereby are given unto us exceeding great and
precious promises, that by these ye might be partakers of
the divine nature, having escaped the corruption
that is in the world through lust.
He provides everything all we need
to live this life victoriously and powerfully for
his glory.
The question that most likely has invaded your mind is a good one.
Again, what is the all that God provides?
Okay, I get it.
You know, I mean, we understand why he provides all things.
That is for our sanctification.
the ongoing process throughout our life on earth of
becoming more and more like Jesus.
It'll end and be in full fruition when we are glorified
and we're really like Jesus in heaven.
But here's the thing.
No Christian can ever claim they cannot be godly.
If you could not, if you did not have the ability to
be godly, only 2 things can be true.
Or one of 2 things can be true.
Sorry.
First off, God would be a liar.
We read the scripture.
Secondly, you are not his child.
Now.
Let's just talk this out, because whenever I
hear preachers talk like that, I kind of cringe, like, wait, someone's
going to clip that and act like you said, God is a liar.
No, no, no.
Here the thing.
The 1st is impossible because God cannot lie.
So it can't be that God is a liar.
It is against his perfect nature and character, so it must be the latter.
We better be careful with what we say we are and are not
able to do as believers.
God demands godliness and provides
all we need to obtain it.
You do realize the Bible tells us that he makes, you say,
well, I just, I'm just tempted and you don't understand my situation and
my environment, and listen, I may not understand your situation
and your environment, but I do understand scripture.
And scripture tells me that he makes a way for escape every
single time that you may bear that temptation.
That's part of the all things.
In other words, listen, you can make a decision.
I'm going to follow the Lord in this situation or this decision,
or I'm not going to.
I'm going to fight this temptation by the power of
Jesus, or I'm going to give in to this temptation by the draw
of the flesh and the lust.
Either way, you have an option.
But again, that still leaves the question of the y'all.
What has God given us?
What freely given things are we talking about?
For this, I want to go to the book of Ephesians.
So everyone turn your Bibles to Ephesians chapter one.
We're going to little Bible study this morning.
Amen?
This is why we're only going through 2 questions instead of five.
When Paul wrote to the church in Ephesus, he outline much of this all
in the very 1st chapter, I believe.
First off, verse 3 says this.
Blessed be the God and Father of
our Lord Jesus Christ, who hath blessed us with all
spiritual blessings in heavenly places in Christ.
So what are those spiritual blessings?
Well, again, if you look at the next verses.
I don't have them on the screen, so that's why I wanted you to turn there.
This is some of the all that we're talking about this morning.
We are chosen in him.
according to verse 4.
We are adopted as his children, according to verse five.
We have been made accepted in the beloved in verse six.
We have been redeemed, that is bought with a price through his
blood in verse seven.
We have been forgiven of our sins in that same verse seven.
We have an abundance of wisdom and understanding in verse 8.
We have been revealed the mystery of his good pleasure and purpose in verse 9.
We have obtained an inheritance in verse 11.
We have been sealed with the Holy Spirit of
promise in verse 13.
Church, listen to me.
We have all things we need to live godly.
But there's more to this too.
This all applies not just to today.
But to eternity as well.
I believe Paul sums it up in Ephesians one,
verse 14, which is the earnest of our inheritance until the redemption of
the purchase possession.
That's us.
unto the praise of his glory.
Church, God did not withhold Jesus from us.
This has an impact not just today.
But for eternity.
Romans 8, 32, he despaired not his own son, but delivered him up for us all.
How shall he then?
Or how shall he not with him also freely give us all things?
Now that word delivered?
We talk about, he did not spare his son.
He did not withhold his own son from us, but delivered him up for us all.
That word delivered means to hand over and to commit.
God didn't hand over Jesus for a one time experience or encounter with Christ.
He handed him over so that whosoever believes in him can be saved
and lived saved.
You know why I believe God teaches in
his scripture eternal security?
It's because if we didn't have it, we could never truly live for him.
I'd just be scared of messing up.
Today, the day, I lose it, God, please.
And I would be so timid in my faith.
I would be so messed up in the head that I would try to do
everything I could to do nothing.
Because as long as I don't do anything, I can't mess up, right?
But see, that's not how he calls us to live.
He saves us.
We have been saved.
We are saved, and we are going to be saved so that we can live
that way today and tomorrow.
He delivered.
He handed over.
He committed him to us, and we are fully equipped for this life for him.
Now, next week, I told you, we're going to go over the final 3 questions, but this morning,
I wonder if we believe what has been written about this.
I want us to examine.
Now think about it.
Paul's speaking to the church at Ephesus.
He's telling them all these spiritual blessings that they've been given.
It's a pretty good list.
I't know about you, but I don't know if I can make a better list.
Amen?
Don't make me say it again.
But let's examine the church of Everson,
because you might be thinking, man, that church must have been rocking.
I mean, you're talking about a church that, man, they
just was exposited, everything they've been given, all these gifts,
all these spiritual blessings, man, there's no way, they didn't have a great ministry.
There's no way they had.
But let's examine.
They were actually one of the 7 churches we see in Revelation that God had a word for.
And what did God say about them?
Revelations chapter 2.
on the screen.
Verse one and three, it says this unto the angels of the church of Ephesus right.
These things saith he that holdeth the 7 stars in his right hand who
walketh in the midst of the 7 golden candlesticks.
I know thy works.
And thy labor, and thy patience, and
how thou canst not bear them which are evil, and thou
hast tried them which say they are apostles, and are not, and hast
found them liars, and hast born, has patience, and for my name's
sake, has labored, and have not fainted.
This right here has proven my point.
Man, this church was rocking.
This church was doing all the right things.
I mean, they were proven apostle.
Oh, you say you're apostle?
Okay.
Let us hear what you got to say.
You're a liar.
Get out of here.
I mean, they were patient.
They were laboring.
They didn't have no problems finding volunteers for nursery or children.
They were doing all the things they should be doing.
Amen.
But what happened?
It sounds like they were using the all.
that we've been freely given.
But what happened?
What else does God say about it?
Well, look at verse 4 and five.
Nevertheless, nevertheless, I
have somewhat against thee.
Because thou hast left Thy 1st love.
Remember, therefore, from where thou art fallen.
And repent and do the 1st works.
Or else I will come unto thee quickly.
And will remove thy candlestick out of his place, accept thou.
Repent.
Cedar Grove this morning, are you walking?
in these spiritual blessings.
What kind of list are we putting as the all for us?
Is the all, well we're growing.
So God's blessed us or, well, we have a lot more kids now, so God's blessed us.
And, well, we have this and we have that.
And man, man, the stage looks amazing and the
worship team and the AV team and the secure, everything is just kind of
working awesome, man.
Man, look at all the things God's blessed us with.
Hear me.
Let us not forget.
how we served God before we had all these things.
Sometimes
I believe that churches get to a point to where man,
they, they, they, they, they, they're doing it and they,
they're growing and everything, but, but because they growing,
because logistics change, and because you got to have to kind of adapt
and all stuff, you forget the 1st works, that she once did.
I remember time.
By the way, God tells us to remember.
I remember a time not too long ago to where our
water bill was up every month because we baptized so many people.
I remember a time, it wasn't, it wasn't, it wasn't a week that went by that
someone didn't tell me, hey, I want you just to pray for this person.
I invited them to church and they're here.
They need Jesus.
I can remember a time not too long ago.
to where this author would be full to the,
I mean, I'm talking about to the 2nd pew with people broken before God.
I remember that time.
I remember when all these things were going.
It didn't matter what we had and what we didn't have.
Man, we had that.
We had a response to God's word.
We had, we had people getting saved.
We had people getting baptized.
We had fellowships that we didn't have to beg people to come to.
Listen, there was a time to where we would we would, we wanted so many kids.
We were praying for more kids, more babies, more toddlers.
Now it just seems like a burden to so many people.
Well, I don't want to walk past that person.
They'll try to get me to help.
The Bible says, remember.
Remember.
Are we living within the gifts of God?
I can tell you what God has not gifted you to.
Sit in that pew.
Lost person can do that.
They don't take talent to sit.
But yet, so many people, it's like, well, my my blessing to this church
is my my attendance.
Come on now.
Oh, we stew it in God's grace well.
Or Have we fell out
of love with the things of God.
Have we become weary and well doing?
Have we stopped the things that we used to so passionately serve God with?
If that's you here this morning, hear me.
Even a church like Ephesus experienced that.
My purpose this morning is not to shame you.
Not even to judge you.
But to encourage you, remember?
Repent.
And do.
Have you been persuaded?